# Abhay Bhardwaj

Software Developer

#### Profile

Frontend Developer with 2+ years of combined IT functional experience including ReactJs, NextJs, and NodeJs with some knowledge of mongodb.

**Programming Concepts:** React, React Native, Redux, Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Next JS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Nodejs.

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, Mongodb

# Work Experience

# Frontend Developer at Hippo Stores

July 2022 — Present

Project:- Unified POS application, OMS Application, Manual Order Application || Technology:- NextJs, MongoDB

Responsibilities:

- 1) Developed Manual Order Application using Next and React.
- 2) Improving the performance of the website for better User Experience.
- 3) Integrated APIs using axios.
- 4) Writing corresponding acceptance test cases as per the requirements and timelines following test-driven development.
- 4) Built Order Management System using NextJs for easier access to all the orders.

#### Software Design Engineer at Merkle Sokrati

May 2021 — May 2022

Project:- Ultratech || Technology:- React, Redux, JQuery, NodeJs, MySQL, AWS

Responsibilities:

- 1) Domain/ Use case understanding as well as requirements gathering and documentation for the project.
- 2) Performing risk analysis, feasibility study of the deliverables before development.
- 3) Writing corresponding acceptance test cases as per the requirements and timelines following test-driven development.
- 4) Designing dynamic components in React and using JSON objects.

## Software Design Engineer Intern at Merkle Sokrati

November 2020 — May 2021

Project:- TCE & Ultratech | Technology:- React, Redux, Nodejs, JQuery

Responsibilities:

#### **Details**

+91 8178217614 abhay.bhardwaj11@gmail.com

#### Links

Github Linkedin

#### **Skills**

**Programming: React** 

Programming: Javascript

Style: CSS

Programming: React Native

Design: Software Design

Operations, Monitoring and Software Management:
GitHub

User Interface: User Interface

DS Algorithm

## Languages

English

Hindi

Analyzing code structure, implementing REST API's and Designing UI for the website.

# Education

## **B-Tech, SRM University**

2017 - 2021

Major: Computer Science Engineering with cloud computing.

SGPA: 7.5

#### CBSE - 12th, Maharaja Aggarasain Adarsh Public School

2016 - 2017

Major: Science with Computers

Percentage: 80%

# **★** Academic Projects

## **Budget Tracker App:**

HTML, CSS, Javascript

An application build using HTML, CSS, Javascript which let user calculate their monthly expenses and help to manage their expenses.

### **Photos App:**

Javascript, React

An application for searching and downloading stock photos.

# Video Player App:

Javascript, CSS, React

Application used to search videos using google youtube API and play them using the iframe tag. Built on react.

#### Corona Tracker App:

#### Javascript, React, Material UI, React Leaflet maps

The application is used to track all the corona cases worldwide and in single states also.

Also, statistics are shown in a bar graph and pie chart.

#### **E-commerce Website**

#### HTML, CSS, NodeJs, MongoDB

Application made using nodeJs for buying and selling consumer goods. Also implemented stripe js for payment functionality.

#### **Spotify Clone App**

# ReactJs, NextJs, Tailwind CSS

Application to play Spotify songs using the Spotify web API and tailwind CSS for designing UI. Users can also able to login and create an acoount.